# Miha Novak

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>GitHub</u>

I am a Senior Mobile Engineer especially interested in building magical mobile experiences, scaling systems up, and shipping reliable applications. I am a good mentor and have several years of experience leading a smaller team on different projects. I enjoy designing a maintainable and scalable codebase with appropriate tests and monitoring it in production.

# **Technologies and Languages**

• Languages: Java, Kotlin, JavaScript

• Technologies: MySQL, BigQuery, Git (GitFlow)

• Other: Data structures and algorithms, AdTech

# **Work Experience**

## **Senior Android Engineer**

**HomeClinico** 

Oct 2021-Jan 2022

Co-founder

- Created the architectural design of the Mobile app and created Android from scratch. Used sensors, **augmented reality**, Kotlin, Room, and Android Studio Profiler to check the performance.
- Created a WordPress/WooCommerce site and optimized the speed by **55%** with caching, media compress, and DNS.
- Integrated Billing and Analytics support to Wordpress/WooCommerce and Android and monitored the traffic.

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Outfit7

Jan 2021-Oct 2021

AdTech team - Android

- Lead Project and Android Engineer of the in-house Consent Management Platform with worldwide legislation support (GDPR TCF v2.0, COPPA, CCPA) (**1 year**). Outfit7's whole user base (**700M users**) had to interact with it. Lead a cross-platform dev team (iOS, Backend, and Frontend) with constant communication with the Legal team. Used Kotlin, architectural patterns, automated tests (unit, integration), events/revenue/crashes monitoring.
- Mentored 3 newcomers on the internal Ad Library and the basics of Mobile Advertising until full proficiency.

Software Engineer III Outfit7 2018–2021

AdTech team - Android

- Lead Android Engineer of the complete Ad Library refactor to support Mobile Headerbidding Advertising (2 years). Used Java, architectural patterns, multithreading, tests (80% CC). Shipped to all Outfit7 apps or 100M daily users.
- Created a Server-to-Server Ad creative (static, video, enriched video) rendering engine within WebView (6 months). Introduced Kotlin to the AdTech Android team which became the default language for all future projects.
- Head Android code performance checker/debugger (memory, CPU, leaks) of the multithreaded Ad Library with the Android Studio Profiler. Reduced memory crashes by 10% and advised external SDK partners on code optimizations.
- Integrated Gameloft rewarded playable Server-to-Server ads and debugged their HTML/Javascript Ad creatives.
- Have worked fully remotely since March 2020. The personal efficiency increased greatly.

Software Engineer II Outfit7 2016–2018

AdTech team - Android

- Head Android and iOS Server-to-Server Ad integration engineer. Collaborated with **10 external** partners and was their main technical contact. Used Java, JavaScript, and HTML for Ad integration.
- Created the first HeaderBidding proof of concept and presented it to an external partner MAX (bought by Applovin)
- Created a Banner Ad identification system for detecting ad providers of inappropriate ads from screenshots. Used by the QA, AdOps, and Customer Support departments. Used Java and custom algorithms to create a web app.
- Monitored revenue/KPIs for the whole AdTech Android traffic daily. Used BigQuery and MySQL.

Native team - Android

- Complete UI refactor of Talking Tom 1 Android game shipped to 500.000 users and added Android TV support.
- Created 2 minigames for the Talking Tom 2 Android game, played by 200.000 users.

#### **Junior Android Engineer**

Infinum

2015

Slovenian Android team

- Created 2 Android apps for external clients used by **10.000** users.
- Collaborated with **remote** cross-platform teams (Frontend, iOS, designers, product managers) and external partners.

#### **Education and Certifications**

• **B.Sc. Computer Science,** Faculty of Computer and Information Science, Ljubljana (25/30 subjects)

2014-Dropout

### **Projects**

- **Programmer's Guide Slovenia** is a collection of useful Slovenian Developer Facebook group posts, resources, and meetups that help kickstart the career of new programmers. The project reached **150+** stars on Github and is used by more than **1.000** programmers and non-technical people. See the source on <u>Github</u>.
- **Broccoli** Slovenian real estate scraper for personal use. Modern API design principles and concepts with Java backend and a **Kotlin** Android app. See the blog post on <u>my blog</u>.
- DrinKing a prototype for an automatic beer dispenser with an Android app payment system. Used Python (Flask) for RBPi client-side, JavaScript/HTML/CSS for user interface, and Java for the backend. Check more on it on my blog.
- **CountOnMe** a sophisticated item counter. The app was made in **Flutter** (Dart) and the Android app was submitted to the Google Play store. As part of Flutter, it uses best practices in declarative programming. More on <u>my blog</u>.
- **Technical blogging** on <u>mihanovak1024 blog</u>. Popular articles include *The Evolution Mobile Ads* and *First Startup Experience*.

## **Interests**

- Volunteer Firefighter with 20 years of membership
- Inline Hockey player with a local inline hockey team (2018 champions of Slovenian 2nd league)